# **FRANCISCO** OLIVARES

#### COMPUTER SECURITY TECHNICIAN **NETWORK SYSTEMS TECHNICIAN SYSADMIN**

I've been using Linux as my main OS for 5 years, I started using Ubuntu, Debian and derivatives. Then Fedora (Red Hat community version) and currently I use Arch Linux.

I'm always expanding my knowledge in everything related to computing, especially in Linux systems, administration and servers.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE



Unitel - Sistemas de Telecomunicaciones

September 2022 - Present

- IT support to customers and users of N1, N2 and N3.
- Switches, APs, Aruba and Cisco routers, 4G routers.
- Office 365 control panel management
- Citrix, Virtualization VmWare
- · Incident resolution, tickets
- · Control of the results of the actions.

#### **SysAdmin**

**Poultry Company** 

April 2019 - January 2022 (2 years, 8 months)

- Linux Server, vsftpd, top, htop, netdata, duplicity, ufw, motion, ethtool, samba, ostickets
- · Windows client-server applications.
- IT Support N1 and N2
- **Definition of strategies** to be followed and their development.
- Control of the results of the actions.
- Windows Desktop Server 2012 Applications and Users
- Linux Server Backups LVM, Duplicity and Clonezilla
- CIA of the company's data
- Networks, TCP/IP, IP cameras, WiFi antennas + automata.
- Raspberry Pi, microcomputing
- DDBB creation, tables add users and make consult ddbb

#### **Systems technician internships**

Fedeto Formación

April 2018 - June 2018 (3 months)

- Windows Server 2010-2012 Active Directory
- Unattended software installation
- IT Support N1 and N2
- Web with Wordpress
- Backups
- . Maintenance, installation and repair of equipment

- Good communication
- Problem solving

**SKILLS** 

- Cybersecurity: ISO 27001 and use of tools.
- · Agility with results
- · More than 5 years of experience with Linux



- in linkedin.com/in/franciscoolivares-martín-165b7b235/
- franciscolivares@protonmail.com
- **(3)** +34 651 563 210

Certificado de soporte de TI de Google

cado de Finalizac

fr4nsys.github.io

#### **FORMATION**

**Ethical Hacking Essentials (EHE)** 

CodeRed - EC-Council 2023

**Digital Forensics Essentials** (DFE)

CodeRed - EC-Council 2023

**Network Defense Essentials** 

CodeRed - EC-Council 2023

**Practical Linux for Security Professionals** 

CodeRed - EC-Council 2023

**Crash Course on Python from** Google

Coursera 2022

Certificado de Profesionalidad en Seguridad Informática

Fedeto Formación 2022

- Cybersecurity
- Linux. Monitoring
- mySQL
- Snort, Wireshark, Nessus
- Metasploit Apache, Nginx
- VMware, Virtualbox
- Elastic Security, Splunk

**Google IT Support Certificate** 

Coursera 2022

**AWS S3 Basics** Coursera 2022

**CFGM Microcomputer Systems** and Networks

LE.S. Valdehierro 2018



• Spanish: native

• English: B2 level



## **CERTIFICATE OF ACHIEVEMENT**

This is to certify that

### Francisco Olivares Martín

Has attended and successfully completed the course

Ethical Hacking Essentials (EHE)

Certificate number

193225

**EC-Council** 

**EC-Council** 

**EC-Council** 

03rd Jan 2023 Jay Bavisi



## **CERTIFICATE OF ACHIEVEMENT**

This is to certify that

Francisco Olivares Martín

Has attended and successfully completed the course

Linux Forensics

Certificate number

Date

193199

03rd Jan 2023 Jay Bavisi



## **CERTIFICATE OF ACHIEVEMENT**

This is to certify that

Francisco Olivares Martín

Has attended and successfully completed the course

Hands-on Binary Analysis in Linux - Part 1

Certificate number

Date

193192

03rd Jan 2023



#### **CERTIFICATE OF ACHIEVEMENT**

This is to certify that

Francisco Olivares Martín

Has attended and successfully completed the course

Linux Hardening Deconstructed

Certificate number

**EC-Council** 

193009

03rd Jan 2023

#### **CERTIFICATE OF ACHIEVEMENT**

This is to certify that

### Francisco Olivares Martín

Has attended and successfully completed the course

Digital Forensics Essentials (DFE)

Certificate number

193247

**EC-Council** 





Date

codered

### **CERTIFICATE OF ACHIEVEMENT**

This is to certify that

Francisco Olivares Martín

Has attended and successfully completed the course

Hands-on Binary Analysis in Linux - Part 2

Certificate number

193209

**EC-Council** 

03rd Jan 2023 Jay Bavisi

codered

Date

## **CERTIFICATE OF ACHIEVEMENT**

This is to certify that



Has attended and successfully completed the course

IT Security with Red Hat Made Easy

Certificate number

193197

Date 03rd Jan 2023

**EC-Council** 



## **CERTIFICATE OF ACHIEVEMENT**

This is to certify that



**EC-Council** 

Has attended and successfully completed the course **Installing and Mitigating Linux Rootkits** 

03rd Jan 2023 193188











